<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SRE on Marvin Murithi | Site Reliability Engineer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sre/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SRE on Marvin Murithi | Site Reliability Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sre/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disaster Recovery and High Availability</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/disaster-recovery-and-high-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/disaster-recovery-and-high-availability/</guid>
      <description>Designed and implemented disaster recovery plans and high availability architectures to minimize downtime and data loss.&#xA;Created Disaster Recovery Plans and Conducted Regular DR Drills Disaster Recovery Plan Template: Developed comprehensive disaster recovery plan templates to ensure consistent and effective recovery procedures. DR Drill Execution Guide: Established guidelines for conducting regular disaster recovery drills, ensuring preparedness and timely response during actual incidents. Deployed High Availability Solutions using AWS, Azure, and GCP AWS HA Architecture: Implemented high availability architectures on AWS using services like Elastic Load Balancing, Auto Scaling, and multi-AZ deployments to ensure continuous service availability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring and Alerting Systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/monitoring-and-alerting-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/monitoring-and-alerting-systems/</guid>
      <description>Designed and implemented comprehensive monitoring and alerting systems to ensure high availability and quick incident response for critical applications.&#xA;Deployed Monitoring Solutions using Prometheus, Grafana, and ELK Stack Prometheus Monitoring Setup: Configured Prometheus to collect metrics from various services, enabling real-time monitoring of system performance. Grafana Dashboards for Application Metrics: Developed Grafana dashboards to visualize key metrics, providing actionable insights into application health and performance. ELK Stack for Log Analysis: Implemented the ELK Stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana) for centralized log management and analysis, facilitating efficient troubleshooting and monitoring.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
